[Music]
hello everybody and welcome to a new
type of video so uh hopefully this will
be the first of a long series there's a
lot of different products I want to
review and so I thought hey why not
start a new series it's not doing enough
things yet add some more seems like fun
and today we're going to be talking
about a new particular line of paints uh
that are called Vallejo acrylic metal
color paints um and so I'm going to talk
about them here in a little detail I'll
just leave that there for a moment and
uh But first you know as I flashed up
there there are some commitments that I
have uh when I'm going to do these
product reviews the first thing I'm
going to do is I'm not going to review
something that I haven't used um and
hopefully a fair amount um I got these a
couple weeks back I have used them quite
a bit uh in the intervening weeks enough
that I feel confident in how they act
and how they work so one of my core
commitments to you with all product
reviews will be that I have used this
thing and I have used it on multiple
models different types of surfaces I've
used the range and I feel good enough in
how I am talking about it okay so that's
number one I'm not just going to get it
that day and throw up a review I don't
care how new or cool it is um but I I do
constantly try to try new things with my
hobby um I'm always trying new tools and
new stuff different brands of paints and
paint brushes and everything else so uh
I want to make sure I share that out
there with people when I find something
I really like and this not to spoil
anything is something I don't just
really like I
love okay uh so let me just get that out
of the way right now um I got turned on
to this from uh somewhere on YouTube I
know Dr fa mentioned it I searched
around there's not really many reviews
of it out there so I thought more people
need to know about this cuz honestly
this is a Wonder
product um so if you watched my hobby
cheating video on steel you know that I
have a real problem with Metals um I
just and what I mean by that is I feel
like it you never really got a real tone
I think the GW Metals steel color Metals
lead belter in the line are basically
garbage that aren't worth putting on a
Model I'll be very clear with that um I
think most of the Steels even produced
by Vallejo are pretty crap um the only
one that is an
exception is the one I showed you in the
previous video which is the uh model air
uh or or model game color which that's
the same thing but the gun gray okay or
chain mail those I think are actually
worth a damn and those were my go-to
steel for a long time and they're fine
there's nothing wrong with
them um but I still wasn't really happy
with them because one of the big
challenges with metal and I cover it in
that previous video is that steel
doesn't really blend very well um and so
you get these really Stark transitions
whenever you move down the the the color
line here okay
um but these Vallejo acrylic metal
colors are an absolute they're sorcery
um they're a ridiculous blend of
excellent coverage and still being
acrylic so there's a lot of really good
Metals out there used in uh normal
hobbying say like model tanks and and
planes and such that are
not uh acrylic okay and the problem with
those is they're very hard to use when
we're doing a model like this because
they're mainly made for airbrushing you
have to have your full respirator on and
be running a vent you blow them through
they're highly toxic all this sort of
stuff they're bad they're hard to work
with but they do produce something that
looks like natural
metal okay um and and previously no one
in acrylics had really cracked the metal
code um and I know as I said in the
previous video a lot of people just slap
metal on something and then watch wash
it and call it a day if that's what you
like you can stop watching this review
you don't need to care about this okay
if you think that looks like metal I'm
not going to attempt to dissuade you
otherwise but that isn't what metal
looks like so if you feel like I do that
you want to get a better steel out of
your painting experience then this is a
product you should look
at okay and we're going to show it in
use I I primed this cannon up so cuz I I
needed something that had a lot of metal
on it and this has a bunch so we can we
can really see what's going on
here and we're going to use this because
again I want to uh show these products
that I review in use so you actually get
a conception of how they work um but
before we do that let's let's move this
out of the way here and let's scoot
these up so let me see if I can bring
them into frame enough to where the
color will will be pretty clear you can
see here
they have there like almost too many to
fit in because I'm really zoomed in so
you'll be able to see it there we go
okay so these are all Steels there are I
think there are 16 different steel
Shades all told so I believe in this
line uh I picked up most of them the
line also contains a glossy black primer
um that is not what I used in that case
I just used a flat dull Vallejo surface
primer and there is also two two uh gold
colors which are a copper and just a
straight gold um I'm not going to cover
those in this video cuz there's only one
of each unlike the steel where they have
this incredible range again because this
is mainly made for hobbyists doing um
say like World War II airplanes right
which would have been primarily steel
colored um and then finally there's a
specific varnish um which is this
water-based glossy metal varnish made
and formulated specifically for these
paints
uh which I did pick up and I I do like
um but as you can see here we start they
we have everything from extremely dark
see if we can get that to come through
there it's very dark it really doesn't
really come through but we'll we'll see
it in a minute um all the way up to
extremely light so here I picked uh
White Aluminum which is a very very
bright color um at the top of the
spectrum you also have a silver and a
chrome um I have Chrome is the only one
I haven't used I've used all all these
in the range exempting Chrome because uh
I for whatever reason I couldn't special
order Chrome and that's okay I've heard
from other reviewers that the their
Chrome is kind of not as good so but I I
if you're looking for Chrome I can't
help you there for the rest of the
colors um I've used them all I like them
all like I said I've got uh I've got 14
of the steel colors I've tried all of
them I like them very
much um one of the things that they
allow you to do not first of all as I
said said previously they have
incredibly good coverage um which is
good for a metal but their pigment is
dense and Hyper fine um as you see here
these are airbrush colors and they will
blow right through your airbrush and
unlike some of the previous metal colors
like even the previous Vallejo metal
colors um these don't gum up your air
your airbrush near nearly as quickly um
they are much much
uh smoother Paints the pigment is even
finer um it's uh they they just have a
much higher density of the small metal
ground pigment which is what you want
with metal the the denser that pigment
the smaller it's ground the more it's
going to look like natural metal okay
all right um the range goes from as I
said very dark with things like gunmetal
gray and magnesium
um and then even their steel color is
actually quite dark if you can see that
um up through a couple different
interesting ones that would be really
great for 40K especially for vehicles
there is a jet exhaust there is a burnt
iron there is an exhaust metal um so you
can do the whole transition with those
three over what an exhaust would look
like from just the the more dull steel
out to where it's actually burning um
and these have a bit of brown tone in
them very shades of brown and red you
probably see that there on the corner
you can kind of see where that ready
that Ruddy Brown tone is gathered um
moving up into the mid tones you have uh
the dark aluminum uh you have a dull
aluminum and a semi matte aluminum um
these are all varying shades of dark
Andor flat gray um Andor sort of midtone
Steel um the dull aluminum and semiat
aluminum are great if you're trying to
do like old beaten
iron or very simple non-polished steel
uh really like those um then we get up
into the higher end r or like the higher
brighter colors you get your Dura
aluminum your pale burnt metal uh your
standard aluminum or aluminium if you
prefer um and then your white uh
aluminum I'm going to say aluminum this
whole time I can't change myself to say
aluminium I'm sure the people who make
this would call it aluminium um and then
finally silver and Chrome
okay so it's a wide range and what's
amazing about these is despite the fact
that they have this great coverage I'm
talking about they also blend really
well okay um the dropper bottles
themselves are 32 Ms um they are
expensive um for I mean they're
reasonably priced for what you get um I
think retail these are about 10 bucks
per dropper bottle um I didn't pay that
you can I'm sure you can find places
like I did that have them cheaper and
sell them at a discount um one of of the
biggest challenges to getting these in
the states is there aren't a lot of
stores that carry them yet um I had to
have my friendly local game store
special order these because they carry a
wide range of vallejos and their
distributor could get them you may need
to reach out to your uh local game store
and see if they could if they carry
Vallejo and see if they could special
order it I know right now it's pretty
much only in a few of the like really
bigger shops like I think I'm pretty
sure Michigan toy soldier has it now and
I think Atomic Empire has these now um
but those are the only two I could find
I think in the states as of several
weeks back when I went digging for it
okay so um the way that they so you got
these big 32 mil pots a little more
expensive but your investment will last
let's take a look at the actual tip
because it's interesting so that's what
the tip of this looks like can you see
that and I think it's coming through
okay this is the hole where the paint
comes out of and this the way this seals
let me let me goe I'm going to shut up
for a second and close
this you hear that hopefully that came
through it really has a tight tight snap
shut and I like that it they seems like
they seal really well um this cap is
this little or paint distribution tip is
so smart because you really don't uh it
doesn't get gummy or waste paint in the
way that a lot of the other dropper
bottles do where you'll get paint up in
the cap um so I'm going to move my
pallet over here into the frame
hopefully we'll get that there we
go okay uhoh look at that that's telling
me I need need to wet my palette a
little more anyway um okay so we're
going to just I'm just going to put a
drop of this down so this is the
gunmetal gray one of the darker colors
in the line the the low end of your dark
black Steels are gunmetal steel and
magnesium as I said so we're just going
to put a drop of that
down and you can see how how dark that
is now I didn't wipe that off look at
the tip there nothing extra nothing else
came out except what I wanted right and
then when I close it
nice solid snap good airtight seal I
mean these are little things but they're
not they're not small things because you
want this stuff to actually work um and
not just dry out on you if you're going
to spend eight or $10 on a on a you know
a bottle of paint I want to know I'm
making an investment that's going to
last for a little while I'm cheap
um okay but I Don't Mind Investing if
something's really good and this is um
so the interesting thing about this as I
had said previously in a video you can't
thin metallics with water um I have
thinned these metallics with water
unlike the model error or game erir and
I have found that they thin with water
just fine no issue um so there we go
like I'm going to drag that around on
the wet pallet just so you can see I'll
spread it out nice and thin and you can
see
how it still retains its consistency now
let's put some of this to use um what
I'm going to do here is I'm going to
take the gunmetal I I grabbed a
selection I can't do all 14 steel colors
uh or you know metal steel colors right
here in this one video um but we'll do a
drop of the regular
steel so I'll kind of keep these in
order on my palette we'll do a j of the
jet exhaust I shook all these up
beforehand as always shake your
paints we'll do a drop of the jet
exhaust right
there you can see the nice rich brown
tone with that look at how nice look at
that nice very almost copper and fused
color isn't that great like for doing
those kind of burnt ends uh we'll do a
drop of the dark
aluminum there we
go we'll do a drop of the dur
aluminum we're just kind of moving up
here and you can see how bright they're
getting and then finally we'll do a drop
of the white aluminium I'm just going to
move back and forth between the two
because now it's making me laugh
all right so there we go that's six this
gives you a good journey around the the
uh the range and you can see the kind of
Base color of all six here from
extremely dark black metal in the gunmal
up to extremely bright in the silver now
let's put these to use I'm going to
scoot these off of pallet but off of
frame but I'll I'll tell you what I'm
using and let's bring our Cannon back on
um so if I'm going to do when I think
about the cannon and how I want to do it
um I'm going to go ahead and start just
with the the steel which is the second
from the darkest and I'm going to do the
cannon Barrel here and some steel and
you'll notice over black primer I am not
making much of a not much of a dent here
okay um I'm really just almost turning
this
metallic right because this is an
extremely dark color and that's not
because of coverage that's just how dark
that steel is
okay now I'm not going to paint the
whole freaking Cannon while while we're
sitting here because this is a product
review not a painting tutorial and I
don't want to take a lot of lot of waste
a lot of your time but I do want to get
a good coverage on here so you can see
what's going on now there's a reason I
started on the steel one of the
interesting things you can do with this
paint that you couldn't really do with
the older metallics is you can really
layer like you can actually layer your
Metals up um I don't it like glazing is
still a little bit tough with these um
you could get away with it but um but
you can do it now okay so I coated that
in steel and as you can see it isn't
much different than than the actual
black primer right that steel out of
this range is very very dark okay but
you can see the shine when I turn it
like that all right so we're going to
and it dries fairly quick um but we're
going to move on uh I'm going to jump up
here to uh my dark aluminum I'm going to
use that to do the bands here so you can
really see what that looks like okay um
so I'm just going to do these little
bands on
the uh whatever you want to call this I
don't know on the thing that holds the
Canon up I don't know Canon
names and I'm just going to knock those
out real quick again I'm not painting
this with any kind of gray plan I'm just
really trying to show off the paints
so as you can see here this is my uh
this is my dark
aluminum um and even the dark aluminum
is pretty
bright and you can see I'm getting
really good coverage out of that right
I'm just running the brush down not
pushing too hard I got all the way
around all of those have not just on
this one brush load haven't went back to
the palette haven't done anything crazy
haven't had to touch it multiple times
really most time it's just once and done
right and I get a nice solid coverage
look at that isn't that amazing like
that's a great metal right there smooth
as butter okay now at this point our
other one up here is
dry and so what I want to do is show you
then how you can layer with this if I if
I set it mixes I want to prove it so I'm
going to take something really high up
there I'm going to take the dur aluminum
which is a much brighter color that's
the second from the highest on what we
had and I'm going to highlight just a
thin line Down the Gun Barrel here okay
for the point of trying to catch like a
light line on this
thing okay
so now if I hold it like that where I
get knock the shine out of it you can
see that that looks pretty silly right
but one of the great advantages to this
paint is that I can take that bring it
on my pet over here I can thin it down I
can grab some of that dark uh or some of
that steel can mix that in
there because these will mix really well
right I could water it down I could use
my glaze mediums or my thinners or
something like that in fact I'm just
going to drop a GL I'm going to grab a
drop of my glazed medium just to prove
to you it works I'm going to actually
drop a little bit of glazed medium into
this
metallic not necessarily
not absolutely necessary but I just want
to prove that it can be done and that it
doesn't break up it actually works
really well and now I've got something
in the
middle so let's get my thumb up here so
we're just going to test there and now
I'm going to run that down the side of
that just smoothing out that that
layer
okay again we're just trying to create a
sort of Illusion of light on this cannon
how it would play
right and
now if we look at that let's knock the
light out of there again you can see how
we've faded the edges there quite a bit
if I let that dry I go over that one
more time I can probably knock that out
completely maybe mix in just a little
more of the dark uh or of the steel
you can see how thin that's applying on
there how easy that is to just blend
that right
together and what's amazing about this
is that is not normally a thing you can
really do with metallics um metallics
don't blend they tend to create very
Stark lines um but here with
this right I'll kind of go I'm just I'm
just playing around now with some
different color
transitions you can see how I can go
back and forth I can grab these colors
and just mix them together and they
blend right into each other these also
have a really nice drying time they they
don't dry super fast I would say they
dry in just the right amount of time
that you want to work with them okay and
you can see now how I've smoothed that
out if we hold it down there I've still
got some Transitions and the
reflectivity of it is going to be very
different depending on where it sits in
the light right if I wanted to darken it
up I could go back and I could grab one
of the other ones
now while that's we're going to let that
dry for just a moment and I want to talk
about these brown tones okay
um because we've also got our jet
exhaust which is that nice Ruddy Brown
tone and so we can see like if I wanted
to tint the end of this Barrel here with
some of that I can do that and I've
watered this down some but you'll notice
I can
almost as I spread that on there you can
see how it just looks like this
wonderful dirty steel great for doing
like your your weapons in 40K if you've
got like some meltas or or dirty gun
barrels or something like that right
look at how wonderful that is as far as
just like dirty metal
goes absolutely Fant fantastic um it's a
really fun tone to work with and I
really like the way that jet exhaust
there's as I said there's a jet exhaust
there's an exhaust metal which is a
lighter tone um and then there's a burnt
iron which is like the sort of very dark
one
um so there you go um and I can keep I
could keep working this around blending
this together like right there I've
still got a fairly sharp line you notice
when I turn the light it kind of Fades
in but I could take that
uh and I could continue to sort of work
with
that and just kind of work my way around
the whole Cannon you know keep it nice
and smooth and what's great is all of
this would blend together without too
much issue and then I've got my gun
barrel nice and good from very dark
metal it's not reflecting much all the
way around up to my super bright metal
and if you look at that line like that's
four or five different colors of metal
working my way around right so let's do
it like this where we can see it very
nicely try to cover as much as the light
dark all the way up to super
bright okay and we don't see those lines
in there anymore the coverage is great
um our ability to do stuff like the
burnt is great uh in the end I really
can't recommend this range enough if we
wanted to go I had one more color on my
palette which I will use quickly just to
show you what that looks like um which
is the White Aluminum that's like your
super
bright so if I wanted to have just um
some
glint you know a place where it's like
really bright kind of retrace my
original line uh I'll put it on
something fresh that way you can see
what it looks like standing alone we'll
just like put it on here you can see how
bright that
is like that is whoa bright so you know
as always you you want to use that
fairly carefully but you can see how
that on the actual Gun Barrel I can use
it to create points of light right or
something like that where I want to get
a specific bright shine or something of
that nature to really capture the the um
the reflection of the the real light and
how it would act on the steel okay so
there you go those are the Vallejo
acrylic metal color
airbrush color paints um if you're a
person who loves working with Steels and
metals you like doing Knights and armor
and stuff like that and I really just
want to take a moment like when you look
at that the the the just very natural
metal look to that the way that the
light actually plays on it the way you
can use the different colors to tint it
right and if I want again if I wanted to
bring it down I could take my darkest
color I could take that gunmetal could
go back to that right and I could go to
my gunmetal and I could just run that
along the bottom and really darken that
way
down here I'll do it on these little
bands so you can see just how much it it
darkens down that
effect
right you can see I can work it thin I
can work it for coverage whatever the
case there we go and I create a really
great natural metal look um
so my final recommendation would be if
you like these kinds of Steels if you
like working in this sort of a color
palette do yourself a favor find a game
store where you can order this stuff
from uh you will not regret it these are
some of my favorite paints I have bought
in a long long time um I absolutely love
them I think they're amazing metal
paints um they are fun to work with it's
fun to see what you can achieve with the
different range I wouldn't necessarily
say hey go in buy the whole stinking
range all at once like I said it is a
little bit on the expensive side
unfortunately um that is the one
downside overall though I got to give
the Vallejo metal color paints uh a big
uh the Vallejo acrylic metal color
paints a big A+ um if I was going to
make a recommendation of what paints you
should be looking at as far as do doing
normal metals and what you would do it's
going to depend a lot on what your work
is like if you're doing 40K and you're
doing a lot of meltas and stuff that
could be very different than if you're
doing fantasy and you want darker Steels
so I would say just aim toward the part
of the spectrum that you really
like okay um so there you go that's the
end of this product review hope you
enjoyed and liked seeing the Vallejo
acrylic metal colors in action uh and as
always we'll see you next time
[Music]